Welcome. In the last lecture, we created this handy function for us to do the climbIkTrace.
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们为我们创建了这个方便的函数来做climbIkTrace。
We are going to look at how we can use the information it provides to place our left
我们将看看我们如何利用它所提供的信息来正确放置我们的左脚
foot correctly. So I'm going to double click to open this function. And the first thing
脚的正确位置。所以我要双击来打开这个函数。而第一件事
that I want to do, so I'm going to promote this head into another local variable as well.
我想做的第一件事，是把这个头也提升到另一个局部变量中。
So I'm going to increase the size of this comma box a bit, then drag these three nodes
所以我要把这个逗号框的大小增加一点，然后把这三个节点拖到这里，并把这个钉子拖出来。
to here and drag out this pin, promote it to another local variable. Click compile,
到这里，然后拖出这个针，把它提升到另一个局部变量。点击编译、
click this drop down to show all the local variables. And I'm going to rename this one
点击这个下拉菜单，显示所有的局部变量。我将把这个重命名为
to heads valid surface head and organize my graph, connect this pin to here, connect this
为有效的表面头，并组织我的图形，将这个针脚连接到这里，将这个
one to here. And I'm going to drag out this heads valid surface head get connected to
连接到这里。我将拖出这个头的有效表面头，连接到
here. All right, click compile. Then the third thing that I want to do instead of this function,
这里。好的，点击编译。然后，我想做的第三件事，而不是这个函数、
so I'm going to drag out this severe trace head location, get it. And I'm going to use
所以我将拖出这个严重的跟踪头的位置，得到它。然后我将使用
a subtract node and I'm going to drag out this input IK bone translation, plug it into socket
一个减法节点，我将拖出这个输入的IK骨骼翻译，把它插入插座
B and the value returning from this pin. So this is how much we should move our bone.
B和从这个针脚返回的值。所以这就是我们应该移动我们的骨头的程度。
But before I connect this to the return node in here, I'm going to use an if node and drag
但是在我把它连接到返回节点之前，我要使用一个if节点，并拖出这个头部有效的表面头部。
out this heads valid surface head. So if we have a valid surface head, drag down these
拖出这个头部的有效曲面头。所以如果我们有一个有效的表面头，拖下这
three nodes, this value here will go through to the final output. And if we don't, a zero
三个节点，这个值就会进入到最终的输出。如果我们没有，一个零
vector will go through to the final output. So connect this to here, place a new node.
矢量将进入最终输出。所以把这个连接到这里，放置一个新的节点。
And I'm going to change the name of it to target bone offset and click compile. And
我将把它的名字改为目标骨骼偏移，然后点击编译。然后
I'm going to go back to this forward solve. So we only want to do this climb trace when
我将回到这个正向求解。所以我们只想在爬升时做这个爬升追踪。
we are climbing. And for that we will need to create another variable to control it.
我们正在爬升。为此，我们将需要创建另一个变量来控制它。
So click this button here to add a new variable. I'm going to call this one should do climb
所以点击这里的按钮来添加一个新的变量。我打算把这个叫做应该做攀登
IK trace and drag it out first, get it and hold down B to bring out the branch node.
IK跟踪，先把它拖出来，得到它，然后按住B键，把分支节点带出来。
So if this condition is true, then I want to do the things in here, which is doing the
所以，如果这个条件是真的，那么我想在这里做的事情，就是进行
trace and fixing the positions of the bone. And same as what we did inside of this function,
追踪和固定骨头的位置。和我们在这个函数中所做的一样、
I'm going to use a sequence node in here as well. So that we'll have a cleaner graph.
我也要在这里使用一个序列节点。这样我们就会有一个干净的图形。
And I'm going to promote the return value of this function into another variable. And
我将会把这个函数的返回值提升到另一个变量中。而且
I'm going to change this name to foot underscore L underscore target offset and move these
我将把这个名字改为下划线L下划线目标偏移，并将这两个节点移到这里。
two nodes up to here. Then I'm going to hold down B to bring out another branch node, connect
两个节点移到这里。然后，我将按住B，带出另一个分支节点，将这个引脚连接到
this pin to here. And for the condition, I'm going to duplicate this get should do climb
这个引脚到这里。对于条件，我将复制这个应做的攀登
IK trace, connect it to here. So if this condition is true, I want to use the return value to
IK跟踪，把它连接到这里。所以如果这个条件是真的，我想用返回值来
set the target offset. And if the condition is false, I'm going to duplicate this node.
设置目标偏移。如果条件为假，我将复制这个节点。
I want to reset this target offset back to a zero vector. All right. That's the first
我想把这个目标偏移量重置为零矢量。好的。这是第一个
thing that I want to do inside of this main control rate graph. And the second thing I'm
我想在这个主控制率图中做的第一件事。第二件事我要
going to run most button click and type in interpolate. So for the value B here, I'm
第二件事，我将运行大多数按钮，并输入内插法。因此，对于这里的值B，我将
going to drag out this target offset get connected to socket B. And for the socket A, I'm going
我将拖出这个目标偏移量，连接到插座B。
to create a new variable. So click this button, change its type to a vector. I'm going to name
创建一个新的变量。所以点击这个按钮，把它的类型改成一个矢量。我将把这个变量命名为
this variable to foot underscore L underscore current offset and drag out this variable get
下划线L下划线目前的偏移量，然后拖出这个变量
connected to socket A and move these three nodes down. So I want to interpolate our current
连接到插座A，并将这三个节点向下移动。所以我想把我们当前的
offset to this target offset. So that will have a smooth transition later for placing
到这个目标的偏移量。因此，这将在以后放置骨骼时有一个平滑的过渡。
our bone. And for the socket T here, I'm going to run most button click and type in delta
我们的骨头。对于这里的插座T，我将运行大多数按钮，并输入delta
time. And I'm going to multiply this delta time with a value. I'm going to change the
时间。我将把这个delta时间与一个值相乘。我将改变
value for socket B here to 30. So this will be our interpreting speed and connect this
这里的插座B的值为30。所以这将是我们的解释速度，并将其连接到
to this socket. And for its return value, I'm going to use it to set this fuel current offset.
到这个插座。对于它的返回值，我要用它来设置这个燃料电流偏移。
So connect this one to here, connect this pain to here. All right. This is the second
所以把这个连接到这里，把这个痛苦连接到这里。好的。这是第二个
thing that I want to do to have a smooth interpreting value. I'm going to move these nodes out a
我想做的第二件事是要有一个平滑的解释值。我将把这些节点移出一些
bit then connect this pin. So the third thing that I want to do in this graph, I want to
然后连接这个引脚。所以我想在这个图中做的第三件事，我想
modify the position of our IK bone. So I'm going to drag out this pin and type in modify
修改我们的IK骨骼的位置。所以我将拖出这个针脚，然后输入修改
transforms. And for this item to modify, this is an array that we can fill in elements to.
transforms。对于这个要修改的项目，这是一个数组，我们可以填入元素。
So I'm going to click this app element and the type is bone. The name is going to be
所以我将点击这个应用元素，类型是骨骼。名称将是
IK underscore foot L and the transform here. I'm going to drag out this foot underscore
IK下划线脚L和这里的转换。我将拖出这个脚下的下划线
L current offset, select get it connected to this translation. And one thing to look out
L的当前偏移量，选择将其连接到这个转换。有一件事要注意
for here is, so this value here is how much we should offset our bone. So we'll need to
这里要注意的是，这个值是我们应该偏移我们的骨头多少。所以我们需要
change its mode from additive local to additive global. So we are adding this value to the
把它的模式从局部加法改为全局加法。所以我们要把这个值加到
original position of our bone. All right. That's the third thing that I want to do,
我们的骨骼的原始位置。好的。这是我要做的第三件事、
modifying the transform of the IK bone. And I'm going to move these nodes to here, then
修改IK骨骼的变换。我将把这些节点移到这里，然后
move these three nodes out. And the last thing that I want to do, I'm going to click this
将这三个节点移出。最后，我想做的是，我将点击这个
app pin. So I'm going to use the IK bone to modify the actual foot bone. So I'm going
应用针。所以我将使用IK骨来修改实际的脚部骨骼。所以我将
to drag out this pin and I'm going to type in full body IK. Since we want to modify the
拖出这个针，然后输入全身的IK。由于我们要修改
position of our bone, it won't be as simple as changing the position value of it. We also
由于我们要修改骨头的位置，这就不是改变它的位置值那么简单了。我们还
need to move other bones to compensate for this change. And this is where full body IK comes in.
我们还需要移动其他骨骼来补偿这一变化。这就是全身IK的用处。
So for the root here, I'm going to change this to pelvis. And for the effectors here,
因此，对于这里的根，我将把它改为骨盆。对于这里的效应器、
this is another array and we need to fill in the actual bone that we want to modify.
这是另一个数组，我们需要填入我们想要修改的实际骨骼。
So click this button to add array element. And in the dropdown here, I'm going to select foot
所以点击这个按钮来添加阵列元素。在这里的下拉菜单中，我将选择足部
underscore L and right mouse button click. I'm going to use the node get transform and the
下划线L和鼠标右键点击。我将使用节点获取转换，我感兴趣的骨头是
bone that I'm interested in is the IK underscore foot L. And I'm going to click this pin to here,
我感兴趣的骨头是IK下划线脚L，我要点击这个针脚到这里、
then click compile. All right, let's test this. So I'm going to click this eye icon. So this
然后点击编译。好的，让我们测试一下。所以我将点击这个眼睛图标。所以这个
variable here can be exposed to our animation blueprint and click compile. Go back to this
变量可以被暴露在我们的动画蓝图中，然后点击编译。返回到这个
app. And inside of the input here, you can see this is the variable that we just exposed. I'm
应用程序。在这里的输入里面，你可以看到这是我们刚刚暴露的变量。我将
going to take this huge pin, click this reference here. I'm going to hold down control and drag out
我要把这个巨大的针，点击这里的参考。我将按住控制键并拖出
this is climbing. So I only want to do this climb IK trace if this is climbing is true.
这就是爬升。所以我只想在 "爬升 "为真时做这个爬升IK追踪。
All right, click compile, then go back to my level, click play. And I'm going to try to clamp.
好了，点击编译，然后回到我的水平，点击播放。我将尝试夹紧。
So we can see the debug shape. That means our control rig is working, but it's kind of in the
所以我们可以看到调试的形状。这意味着我们的控制装置在工作，但它是一种在
way that we can see if the placement is correct. So I'm going to disable that, go back to this
我们可以看到位置是否正确。所以我将禁用它，回到这个
control rig. I'm going to scroll up to this function, untick this show debug shape. And I
控制装置。我将滚动到这个功能，取消对显示调试形状的勾选。而我
found out that I forgot to connect this pin to here. Make sure you double check your graph to
我发现我忘了把这个引脚连接到这里。请确保你仔细检查你的图形，以
prevent errors like this. All right, I'm going to click compile, then go back to my level and
防止这样的错误。好的，我将点击编译，然后回到我的关卡，再按下播放键。
press play again, try to climb up and you can see it's working.
再按下播放键，试着往上爬，你可以看到它在工作。
When we're climbing, I'm going to go to this surface here. Our left foot is clipping through
当我们在爬的时候，我要到这个表面去。我们的左脚正穿过
the surface. So our trace is working. And now we need to provide this some offset since what we
表面。所以我们的跟踪是有效的。现在我们需要提供一些偏移，因为我们的
want here is we want to snap the tip of our foot to the surface and not the entire foot. All right,
这里要的是我们要把脚尖扣在表面，而不是整个脚。好的、
go back to my control rig graph. I'm going to double click to open this function. And I'm going
回到我的控制平台图。我将双击来打开这个功能。然后我将
to give it a new function input. So click this button to add a new element changes type to a
给它一个新的函数输入。所以，点击这个按钮，添加一个新的元素变化类型为
float. And I'm going to change its name to target location offset. And I'm going to adjust its order.
浮子。我将把它的名字改为目标位置偏移。我还要调整它的顺序。
So connect this pin in here to move this parameter up and click compile. And I'm going to move to
所以连接这里的针脚，将这个参数向上移动，然后点击编译。然后我将移动到
this subtract node in here. So for the final location, before we output it, I'm going to drag
这里的减法节点。因此，在我们输出之前，对于最后的位置，我要把它拖出来并使用另一个减法节点。
it out and use another subtract node and connect this drop down and right mouse button click to get
并使用另一个减法节点，连接这个下拉菜单，然后点击鼠标右键来获得
the function input that we just created. So get target location offset and connect it to this Y
我们刚刚创建的函数输入。所以得到目标位置的偏移，并将其连接到这个Y
and connect this pin to the true socket. Now we should have the ability to offset the foot
并把这个引脚连接到真正的插座上。现在我们应该有偏移脚的能力了
and click compile. Go back to this forward self. So I'm first going to try a value of 20 units
并点击编译。回到这个向前的自我。所以我首先要尝试一个20单位的值
and see what this feels like. All right, go back to our level. I'm going to try again, try to climb up.
看看这是什么感觉。好了，回到我们的水平。我准备再试一次，试着往上爬。
And you can see this time it works much better.
你可以看到这次的效果要好得多。
Maybe 20 units is a bit much.
也许20个单位有点多。
I'm going to decrease it to 15 for our left foot and compile. Try again.
我要把我们的左脚减少到15，然后编译。再试一次。
So I think 15 is not quite enough, maybe 18.
所以我认为15是不太够的，也许是18。
And try again.
再试一次。
I think 18 works better for the left foot. I'm going to try to move to the right
我认为18对左脚来说效果更好。我将尝试向右移动
and move down, move up.
并向下移动，向上移动。
Great. I think it's working really well.
很好。我认为它的效果非常好。
So just a quick summary. In order to achieve what we want, we need to get hold of the target offset
因此，只是一个简单的总结。为了达到我们的目的，我们需要掌握目标的偏移量。
and with our head location and the bone location, we can get just that. After this step, don't forget
而有了我们的头部位置和骨骼位置，我们就可以得到这个。在这一步之后，别忘了
to interpolate the value so that we'll have a smooth transition. Then all we need to do is
插值，这样我们就会有一个平滑的过渡。然后我们需要做的就是
modifying the IK bone and use the IK bone to modify the actual foot bone. And very likely,
修改IK骨，并使用IK骨来修改实际的脚骨。而且很有可能、
same as what you just saw, your foot will clip through the surface and that's where the foot
和你刚才看到的一样，你的脚会穿过表面，这就是脚的位置
clip through the surface and that's where the horizontal offset comes in. This value here can
这就是脚穿过表面的地方，这就是水平偏移的地方。这个值可以
help us to manually adjust the position for our foot. So feel free to refer back to the video if
帮助我们手动调整我们的脚的位置。所以，如果你需要帮助，可以随时参考视频。
you need help. And it's time for you to do the same. And I'll see you in the next lecture.
你需要帮助。现在是时候让你做同样的事情了。我们在下一个讲座中再见吧。
[Music]
[音乐]